How easy is it to get TRT? Or maybe how
can I get my doctor to prescribe me TRT?
How do I get uh it in in general?
>> Right. Yeah, it it should be easier than
it is. And a lot of uh a lot of people
get shut down pretty quick. So, um
you know, in in um you know, in standard
medicine, you go to your primary care
doctor. There's a couple of things. One
is sometimes they just they just don't
know a lot about it. Uh, and then if
they do know a lot about it, you have
to, you know, have them willing be
willing to actually prescribe this
stuff. So, one, you have to get them to
run the test in the first place. That's
that's your first hurdle. So, you go to
your primary care doctor. Uh, why do you
want to run this test in the first
place? If you're lucky, they run the
test. And now you get your levels back.
They look at these levels. They say,
"Hey, look at this. It's in normal
range." Or, "Oh, it's just below normal
range. That's close enough. You're
getting old. Don't worry about it." Uh
the next barrier there is even if they
did check a total testosterone, they
probably didn't get a free testosterone.
Whether that's, you know, done directly
or more ideally they did it calculated
by getting some other lab numbers like
an SHPG um to kind of calculate that
number because that number is the more
important number and the one that's most
correlated with symptoms and it's the
number you want to see. So you could
have a a normal looking total
testosterone where in the meantime your
free testosterone is falling in the
background and probably is as your
aging. It really does for for everyone
as your SHPG goes up. It binds up that
uh that total testosterone. So you have
all these factors to get past. Um and
now a lot of times the bottom line is
your primary care doctor won't or can't
do it and they just it's just not going
to happen.
Even if you do get him to do it, the
chances of him giving you a good
protocol are pretty terrible. I I hear
from guys daily telling me about these
ridiculous things where their doctors
giving them some low super low dose it's
not even enough to overcome their own
natural low levels that they've that
they've, you know, gotten to or it's an
amount that's given so infrequently it's
just not going to be effective. Maybe
they'll feel good for a few days like
they're getting a shot once every two
weeks, that kind of thing. then they
report back to their doctors not feeling
great that you know the primary care
doctor says well I guess it doesn't work
for you they quit and go away. Uh so you
know so the bottom line is is you know
if you find someone a primary care
doctor who's really into this kind of
thing and knows what they're doing and
interested in helping you with it might
work. Uh but for the most part you're
better off going to a place that
specializes in this kind of thing. And
there's you know there's many clinics
around that do do this sort of you know
do this sort of thing. That's the reason
why it's become such a you know such a
big thing. Um there's a big a big gap in
the um you know standard medicine as far
as that goes.
>> Yeah, you you guys in the United States
actually are very lucky because you have
a lot of men's health clinics, TRT
clinics uh here in Europe. You really
have to try hard to find one.
>> Sure. Sure. And I'll mention too, I
mean, like anything else, any other
business or anything else you run into
in life, there's going to be varying
qualities there, too. So really vet vet
the place you're, you know, you're
talking to. Ask ask the right questions.
go in a group like yours and see what
the basics are and come in as a as an
informed consumer.
>> You can avoid
avoid the setbacks you get from having
some bad treatment for years before you
finally get it straight. So, so it's
possible. It definitely takes some leg
work on the, you know, by the consumer.
And unfortunately, it's not as easy as
just talking to your primary care doctor
about it most of the time.